nursingtimes.net 2015-10-21

# Nursing Times Privacy Policy

EMAP Publishing Limited ( **We** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We gather/use and keep information in line with the Data Protection Act 1998 and all relevant regulations.

This policy (together with our [terms of use](http://www.nursingtimes.net/terms-and-conditions/) and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the **Act** ), the data controller is EMAP Publishing Limited of c/o Top Right Group Limited, The Prow, 1 Wider Walk London W1B 5AP.

### INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

We may collect and process the following data about you:

* **Information you give us.** You may give us information about you by filling in data on our site www.nursingtimes.net ( **our site** ) or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our service, participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on our site, enter a competition, promotion or survey, carry out training, enter information in connection with or otherwise deal with or alter your training record and when you report a problem with our site. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information, personal description and photograph, training record and/or details of your employer or employees.

* **Information we collect about you.** With regard to each of your visits to our site we may automatically collect the following information:

  * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform;
  * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

* **Information we receive from other sources.** We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

### COOKIES

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Cookie policy (below).

**USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

* **Information you give to us.** We will use this information: 

  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
  * to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about;
  * to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about goods or services we feel may interest you. If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale or negotiations of a sale to you. If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the setting page [http://www.nursingtimes.net/account/my-newsletters](http://www.nursingtimes.net/account/my-newsletters/));
  * to notify you about changes to our service;
  * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; and/or
  * If someone pays for your subscription on your behalf, to advise and update them or their nominees of your log in records, your training records, and performance in training courses, any feedback you have given about the training modules and any and all other information in connection with your training or the use of the site.

* **Information we collect about you.** We will use this information: 

  * to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * to improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;
  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you;
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about goods or services that may interest you or them;
  * if your employer pays for your subscription, to advise and update them of your training records and performance in training courses and all other information in connection with your training.

* **Information we receive from other sources.** We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

### DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may share your information with selected third parties including:

  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you and other third parties subject to them being under an obligation of confidentiality in respect of the information they receive.
  * Advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and serve relevant adverts and marketing to you and others.
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Emap Publishing Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply [our terms of use](http://www.nursingtimes.net/terms-and-conditions/) and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of EMAP Publishing Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at customerservices@nursingtimes.net.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### ACCESS TO INFORMATION

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

### CONTACT

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to customerservices@nursingtimes.net.

## 5\. Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your mobile device, tablet or computer's hard drive.

We use the following cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services. 
  * **Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below: 

Cookie name | Purpose  
---|---  
ARPT | This is a technical session cookie set by our website to share the number of visitors we get on our site between web servers. This is so the site does not get overloaded and can perform at its optimum potential  
ASP.NET_SESSIONId | This session cookie tells us that you are actively using our site. This way we can always know, at any given time, how many users we have visiting.  
SSOEX_[ID] | This tells us whether you are logged into our site  
emapauth | This cookie supports the linking of subscriptions between our different products  
tempid | Similar to the emapauth cookie, this supports the linking of subscriptions between our different products  
.ASPXAUTH | This cookie is used to store an encryption key of the users authentication after login so that they remain authenticated during their session on the website  
MoodleSession | This cookie is used to track user session must be allowed to allow moodle/totara to work  
MOODLEID: | This cookie holds your userid if you select remember username on login (not required)  
  
Certain cookies are either set by third parties on the Website or these are set by us using the third parties cookie code. More information about cookies placed by third parties and how to restrict or block their cookies can be accessed by following the link to their website. In addition to cookies, tracking gifs may be set by us or third parties in respect of your use of the Site. Tracking gifs are small image files within the content of our site or the body of our newsletters so we or third parties can understand which parts of the website are visited or whether particular content is of interest. 

Cookie name | Purpose | More Information  
---|---|---  
Adtech | Adtech is EMAP's online ad server used for serving and tracking advertisements across the EMAP websites | [Adtech Cookie opt-out](http://www.adtech.com/cookie_opt-out)  
Webtrends   
WT.FPC | WebTrends uses a cookie to track the number of unique users of this website. It basically tells us whether the website has a small number of regular visitors or a large number of infrequent visitors. The cookie only relates to what goes on in this website | [WebTrends Privacy Policy](http://webtrends.com/privacy-statement/)  
Google Analytics   
_utma   
_utmb   
_utmc   
_utmz | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. | [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
comScore | Comscore help us to provide online surveys and video content through our Site. Comscore use cookies so that they can provide anonymous statistics on the interaction of users with these online surveys or video content. | [comScore Privacy Policy](http://www.comscore.com/About_comScore/Privacy_Policy)  
AddThis | AddThis helps us to integrate social media sharing tools into our website such as facebook or twitter and to measure the effectiveness of these sharing tools | [AddThis opt-out](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out#.T3FyoHmx2Sp)  
DoubleClick (Google) | Doubleclick use a cookie when they serve advertisements in order that they can deliver reports on the effectiveness of these advertisements on our Site. The cookie records what advertisements the user has seen and how often | [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy/ads/)  
Optify   
_opt_gvi | Optify collects information about End User activity on the Site, including a unique Optify Customer ID, the End User’s IP address, the URL of the “referring” Web page (i.e., the page viewed by the End User prior to visiting the tracked page on your Site), the title and URL of tracked pages on the Site, and information about pages visited and actions taken. The Javascript code makes a “call” to our Software Services where, relying on third party service providers, we use the IP address to identify company name and approximate geographical location for the End User. | [Optify Privacy Policy](http://www.optify.net/about-our-b2b-inbound-marketing-solutions/privacy)  
__utma:   
_utmb &   
_utmc:   
_utmv:   
_utmz: | The following 4 cookies are used by Google analytics to check the sites performance | <https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage>  
dle_support (not required) | Stores the results of all the browser checks |   
  
## 6\. Third Party Websites

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site. 

## 7\. Registration

  1. To access certain parts of the Emap websites, Emap may require you to register and provide certain information about yourself.
  2. You are reminded that in addition to the provisions of this Privacy and Cookies Policy, where you register you also agree to:   
a. provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself as prompted by the relevant registration form (such information being the "Registration Data"); and   
b. maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it fully up to date.
